Henry Allen Moe Papers 1920-1975 Mss.B.M722
American Philosophical Society
- Henry Allen Moe Papers, 1920-1975; 120 lin. feet (Box 1-344)
  - Krusé, Cornelius
  - Kubik, Gail
  - Kuhlmann, C B
  - Kuhn, Charles L
  - Kuhn, Thomas
  - Kulla, Elmer
  - Kuntz, Paul G
  - Kuper, Theodore Fred
  - Kurrelmeyer, B
  - Kurti, Nicholas
  - Kurtz, Florence G
  - Kuttner, Stephan
  - Kutz, Sol and Marcia
  - Labarca, Amanda
  - Labbitt, Ray W
  - Labouisse, Henry R, Jr.
  - Lacerda, Osvaldo Costa
  - Lacy, Elizabeth
  - Ladner, Gerhart B
  - LaFarge, C Grant
  - La Farge, John
  - La Fetra, Gladys A
  - Lafferty, C J
  - La Fleche, Duane
  - La Gatta, Frances
  - Laggren, Mrs. Robert I
  - Laidlaw, Mrs. James Lees
  - Laires, Fernando
  - Lake Forest College
  - Lake George Historical Association
  - Lake, John A K
  - Lake, K
  - Lake Mauweehoo Club
  - Lalor Foundation
  - Lambert, Richard D
  - Lambert, Robert A
  - La Mer, Victor K
  - Lamont, Mrs. Florence and Mrs. Elizabeth C. Morrow
  - Lamont, Thomas W
  - Lamson, Roy
  - Lancaster Press
  - Land, Aubrey C
  - Land, Edwin B
  - Landeau, Jean
  - Landis Valley Museum
  - Landman, J Henry
  - Lane, Howard
  - Lane, John T
  - Lane, Robert P
  - Lanford, Oscar E
  - Lange, Dorothea
  - Lange, F C
  - Lange, Francisco Kurt
  - Langer, William L
  - Langner, Lawrence
  - Lapidus, Martin
  - Lark, Charles T
  - La Roche, Chester J
  - La Rose, Mrs. Winifred
  - Larrabee, Eric
  - Larson, Bruce P
  - Lasker, BrunoLaski, Harold J
  - Laski, Harold J
  - Latin America - General
    - Books
    - Caldwell, R G
    - Escobar, Caballero Alfredo
    - Escuela Agricoloa Pan Americana
    - Esposito, Michael
    - Evans, Clifford
    - Funds
    - Garcia, Godofredo
    - Jones-Odriozola, Guillermo
    - Kroeber, Alfred L
    - Lamela, Felix
    - Lanning, John T
    - Latcham, Ricardo
    - Latorre, Mariano
    - Lectures
    - Lehmann, Carlos
    - Lipschütz, Alejandro
    - Miscellaneous requests
    - Navarro, José Gabriél
    - Ocampo, Victoria
    - Onis, Frederico de
    - Osorio de Almeida, Miguel
    - Pach, Walter
    - Panama (Ruth F. Voight; Esther de Calvo)
    - Parodi, Lorenzo R
    - Passenger lists
    - Pettoruti, Emilio
    - Picon-Salas, Mariano
    - Pierson, Donald
    - Pomona College
    - Portinari, Candido
    - Prendergast, Walter T
    - Price, Llewellyn Ivor
    - Progressive education
    - Quine, Willard V
    - Rankin, Thomas
    - Ravignani, Emilio
    - Redfield, Robert
    - Reeves, R G
    - Reissig, Luis
    - Rich, Daniel Catton
    - Rickett, H W
    - Robbins, J Stanton
    - Robson, Elinor D
    - Rojas, Jorge Muelle
    - Rosario, University of.
    - Rothschild, John
    - Rundle, Walter
    - Salvado, Carlos
    - Samper-Ortega, Daniel
    - Sanchez, Luis Alberto
    - Schlesinger-Carrera, Luis
    - Schneider, Herbert W
    - Scholarships, Students
    - Sears, Mary
    - Sedgwick, Ellery
    - Segura, Alfonso
    - Selye, Hans
    - Simonson, Joseph
    - Smith, Carleton Sprague
    - Spaeth, Sigmund
    - Spier, Leslie
    - Spinden, Herbert J
    - Stettinius, Edward R, Jr.
    - Steward, Julian
    - Stockton, Ernest L
    - Students
    - Students' International Union
    - Suggestions
    - Taylor, Francis Henry
    - Tello, Manuel
    - Thurber, Donald
    - Thomas, W Stephen
    - Thomson, Charles A
    - Torres, Heloisa Alberto
    - Umlauff, Teresa
    - Urey, Harold C
    - Vaillant, George C
    - Valcarcel, Luis Eduardo
    - Vassar College
    - Vianna-Moog, Clodomir
    - Villa-Lobos, Heitor
    - Visa requirements
    - Vogt, William
    - Vouchers
    - Wagley, Charles
    - Walters, Carl
    - Wambaugh, Sarah
    - Waples, Douglas
    - Ward, R D
    - Wetmore, Alexander
    - Whitaker, Arthur P
    - Williams, Jesse F
    - Zahner, Louis C
    - Zamora, Juan C
    - Zavala, Silvio
    - Zwemer, Raymond L
  - Lattimore, Richard
  - Lau, Ethel C Elkins
  - Laurence, Dan H
  - Lauro, Rafaella
  - Lautner, Joseph
  - Lavin, Mrs. Mary
  - Law, Mouzon
  - Lawrence, Mrs.
  - Lawrence, John T
  - Lawrence, Pauline
  - Lawrence, Richard W, Jr.
  - Lawson, Harry F
  - Lawson-Johnston, Peter
  - Lax, Stephen Girard
  - Lay, Charles Downing
  - Lay, David
  - Lay, George Cowles
  - Lay, Mrs. Laura
  - Lazansky, Mauricio
  - Leach, Henry Goddard
  - Leach, J P
  - Leaf, Edward N
  - League of Composers
  - Leakey, Richard E
  - Leakey, Richard, Foundation
  - Leamy, Robert J
  - Lear, John
  - Leary, Mrs. Eleanor
  - Leatherman, Le Roy
  - Leatherstocking Corporation
  - Le Brun, Mrs. Rico (Constance)
  - Lechliter, Irvin
  - Leddy, T A
  - Le Doux, Louis V
  - Lee, C L
  - Lee, R W
  - Lee, Raymond A
  - Lee, Rensselaer W
  - Lee, Ronald F
  - Lefevre, Mrs. Edwin
  - Lefkovitz, Herbert
  - Lefkowitz, Louis J
  - Lehman, Herbert H
  - Lehninger, Albert L
  - Leigh, Robert D
  - Leighton, George R
  - Leighton, John
  - Leighton, Josephine G
  - Leiser, Mrs. Sylvia
  - Leisy, Clifford, and Ruth
  - Leitzia, Angelo
  - Lekus, Max
  - Leland, Marine
  - Leland, Simeon E
  - Leland, Waldo G
  - Lennie, Daphne (Mrs. D M)
  - Lenroot, Katharine F
  - Leon, Fernando
  - Leonard, L Larry
  - Leong, Linda
  - Leontief, Wassily
  - Lerner, Edward
  - Lerner, I Michael
  - Lerner, Mrs. Ruth
  - Le Roux, William, S.J.
  - Lesser, Joseph
  - Lester, Irwin D
  - Lester, Robert M
  - Letiche, John M
  - Levene, Mrs. Victoria
  - Levens, Robert
  - Levens, Mrs. Robert
  - Levertov, Denise
  - Levi, Julian
  - Levy, David M
  - Levy, Lawrence H
  - Levy, Naphtaly
  - Lewis, Edwin O
  - Lewis, L H
  - Lewis, Robin
  - Lewis, Warren M
  - Lewis, Wilmarth S
  - Lewisohn, Irene
  - Lewisohn, Mrs. Paul
  - Lewisohn, Sam A
  - Libby, Leona Marshall
  - Libby, W F
  - Library of Congress
  - Libreria Universitaria
  - Lieberman, William
  - Lief, Arthur
  - Life Insurance Medical Research Fund
  - Lilienthal, David E
  - Lima, A M Da Costa
  - Limmer, Dorothy
  - Limmer, Ruth
  - Lincoln Center
  - Linden, Jack
  - Lindfors, Robert F
  - Lindley, Dan
  - Lindley, Denver
  - Lindley, Ernest K
  - Lindquist, Kenneth H
  - Lindsay, John V
  - Lindsay, Kenneth
  - Linstrom, Mariolyn
  - Lingelbach, William Ezra, and Edwin O. Lewis
  - Linton, M Albert
  - Lioger, Alain
  - Lipmann, Charles B
  - Lisle, Claire
  - Lismer, Arthur
  - Lissim, Simon
  - Litchfield Natural Gas Company
  - Littell, Norman M
  - Littell, Robert
  - Little, Joseph C
  - Livanos, Kakia
  - Lizardi, Maria Esperanza
  - Lizarralde, Ignacio Copete
  - Lloyd, Mrs.
  - Lloyd, Francis V
  - Lloyd, Morris
  - Lloyd, Norman
  - Lober, Georg
  - Lock, Robert
  - Locke, Alain
  - Locke, C R
  - Lockwood, Henrietta Sedgwick
  - Lockwood, John E
  - Lockwood, Willard A
  - Locsin, Leandro V
  - Loeb, Betsy
  - Loeb, Ella-Marie
  - Loeb, Emily
  - Loeb, Robert F
  - Loeb, Willard
  - Loeb, Mrs. Willard
  - Loengrad, Margery Borg
  - Loengrad, Richard O
  - Logan, Douglas
  - Logan, Harlan
  - Lohmann, Carl A
  - Lomask, Milton
  - Lomenzo, John P
  - Long, Boaz
  - Long, Clarence
  - Long, J D
  - Long, Jack
  - Long, John C
  - Lopez-Rey, José
  - Lord, Clifford L
  - Lord, Joseph
  - Loree, Mrs. Elizabeth
  - Lost, Robert
  - Lottinville, Savoie
  - Lotz, Rose
  - Loveland, E R
  - Lovell, Malcolm
  - Loveman, Amy
  - Lovett, Robert A
  - Lovitt, John V
  - Lowe, E A
  - Lowes, John L
  - Lowie, Mrs. Luella Cole
  - Lowie, Robert H
  - Lowry, Bates
  - Lowry, W McNeil
  - Lubell, Samuel
  - Lubin, Isador
  - Lubin, Steven
  - Luce, Henry, Foundation, Inc.
  - Luco, Joaquin V
  - Ludlum, C A
  - Luening, Otto
  - Lund, Orville J
  - Lundbergh, Holger
  - Lundeen, David
  - Lundeen, Ernest
  - Lundell, Ernest M, Jr.
  - Lundell, Mr. and Mrs. Ernest M
  - Luomala, Katharine
  - Lutton, C E
  - Lutz, Edward
  - Lutz, Louise
  - Lux, Eugene
  - Lux, Gwen
  - Luyten, Willem J
  - Luzac & Company
  - Lydenberg, Harry M
  - Lyman, Charles P
  - Lynch, Frank R V
  - Lynes, Carlos
  - Lynes, Russell
  - Lynn, Mrs. G E
  - Lyon, Cecil B
  - Lyon, Charles S
  - Lyon, E Wilson
  - Lyon, Stuart R
  - Lyons, Clifford P
  - Lyons, Roger
  - McAlpin, David H
  - McAndrew, John
  - McAneny, George
  - McBride, Pierre B
  - McCall, John Oppie
  - McCalmon, George
  - McCann, Anna Marguerite
  - McCleery, William
  - McClellan, Bruce
  - McClure, Roy D
  - McClure, Stewart
  - McCollester, Parker
  - McColough, Virginia, and Jane Marx
  - McConagha, Glenn L
  - McConnell, T R
  - McConnell, Vincent
  - McCord, Robert
  - McCormack, Elizabeth
  - McCormick, Mrs. Chauncey
  - McCormick, Kenneth
  - McCoy, Mrs. Cecil
  - Macrae, Elliott B
  - McCray, Porter
  - McCroy, R A
  - McCutcheon, Victor
  - MacDermott, TerenceWW L
  - McDiarmid, E W
  - McDonald, John J
  - McDonald, P H
  - Macfadyen, John H
  - McFarland, Ross A
  - MacFarlane, Janet R
  - McFeatters, Dale
  - McGannon, Donald H
  - McGee, Anne
  - McGhee, Paul A
  - McGill, William J
  - McGilvrey
  - McGowan, Kenneth
  - McGrath, Christopher C
  - McGregor, Geddes
  - McHenry, Dean
  - McHenry, E
  - McIntyre, John
  - MacIver, Robert M
  - McKee, Elmore
  - McKelvie, C L
  - McKelway, Benjamin M
  - McKenzie, Frederick
  - McKeon, Richard P
  - McKibben, F H
  - McLanathan, Richard
  - MacLane, Saunders
  - MacLane, Mrs. Saunders
  - Mac Lean, K Sheldon
  - Mac Lean, M S
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - MacLeish, William H
  - MacLuath, V.
  - McManus, Robert L
  - McMenamin, Edward B
  - Macmillan Company
  - McNair, Robert E
  - Mac Namara, Paul
  - McNichol, Charles E
  - McNulty, Kneeland
  - MacShane, Frank
  - Macchiavello, Atilio
  - Maceda, José
  - Mackay, Mark W
  - Mackel, James P
  - Maclay, Mark W
  - Macy, John W, Jr.
  - Madariagas, S
  - Madison, Ward
  - Magill, Roswell
  - Maher, Alice
  - Mai, L H
  - Maier, John
  - Main, Charles E
  - Main, Kenneth
  - Main, Laura
  - Maitland letters
  - Maland, Dorothy
  - Maland, Oswald
  - Malderelli, Oronzo
  - Malenchini, Manuel
  - Mallon, Mrs. John Howard
  - Mallory, Walter H
  - Malone, Dumas
  - Malone, Elisabeth
  - Maloney, Francis T
  - Maloney, Thomas J
  - Malraux, André
  - Mandel, H Robert
  - Mañe-Nin, Roberto
  - Mangelsdorf, Paul C
  - Manhattan Storage & Warehouse Company
  - Manhattanville College
  - Mann, Marion
  - Manning, Charles A W
  - Mansfield, John
  - Manship, Mrs. Isabel
  - Manship, Paul
  - Mantell, Harold
  - Manzer, H W
  - Mapel, William
  - Marañón, Gregorio
  - Marceau, Henri
  - Marchand, Pierre
  - Marder, Arthur J
  - Maremont, Arnold H
  - Margoulies, Berta
  - Mariani, Charles X
  - Markle, John and Mary, Foundation
  - Marquis, A. N., Company
  - Marr, James H
  - Marroney, Peter R
  - Mars, Louis P
  - Marschak, Jacob
  - Marsden, Susan
  - Marsh, Gordon
  - Marshall, Charlotte G
  - Marshall, E K
  - Marshall, James E
  - Marshall, John
  - Marshall, Lauriston C
  - Marshall, Mrs. Mary
  - Marshall, Nelson
  - Marshall, Roger D
  - Martha Graham Foundation for Contemporary Dance
  - Marti, Samuel
  - Martin, D C
  - Martin, Dan M
  - Martin, Ephraim
  - Martin, Mrs. Florence
  - Martin, Geoffrey J
  - Martin, John
  - Martin, Keith
  - Martin, Mrs. Mae
  - Martin, Malachi
  - Martin, S Walter
  - Martindell, Jackson
  - Martinelli, Ezio
  - Martinez, Carlos
  - Martinez del Rio, Pablo
  - Martins, Maria
  - Marvin, H M
  - Mary Imogene Bassett Hospital
  - Mary Imogene Bassett Hospital Ad Hoc Committee on Research
    - Agreement with Blue Cross
    - Annual Financial reports
    - Annual reports
    - Appraised inventory
    - Board of Trustees meeting
    - Executive Committee
    - Financial reports
    - Hermann, William H
    - Minutes
    - New director file
    - Recommendations and findings
    - Retirement plan
  - Mason, Dorothy E
  - Mason, Edward S
  - Mason, Elizabeth
  - Mason, L Randolph
  - Massachusetts Historical Society
  - Mater, Timothy
  - Mateus, Emilio
  - Mather, Kirtley F
  - Matheson, Scott M
  - Mathew, Mrs. Gladys
  - Mathews, Henderson
  - Mathews, Howard B
  - Mathias, James F
  - Matsuoka, Yosuke
  - Matteson, Mrs. Bartow V V
  - Matthews, H G
  - Mattson, Wallace
  - Mauck, Willfred
  - Maue, Harry H
  - Mauer, Francis J
  - Maufe, Lady Prudence
  - Mauwe, Richard
  - Mauzey, Merritt
  - Mavalankar, P G
  - Maxey, E Stanton
  - Mayer, Clara W
  - Mayer, Frederick C
  - Mayer, Grace M
  - Mayer, Sir Robert
  - Mayor, A Hyatt
  - Mayor's Committee
  - Mazzola, John W
  - Mead, Theodore
  - Meade, Devon
  - Meade, Robert D
  - Means, J H
  - Means, Philip
  - Mechau, Dorik V
  - Medallic Art Company
  - Medawar, Peter
  - Medem, Federico
  - Medical Internes
  - Medina, Harold R
  - Medley, John
  - Mednick, Sol
  - Meehan, Ellen
  - Meeking, A
  - Meeks, Everett V
  - Mees, C E K
  - Mehta, Ved
  - Meiss, Millard
  - Melville, John C, Jr.
  - Melville, Ward
  - Memoranda
  - Memorandum: Analysis of the not-for-profit corporation law
  - Mencke, John B
  - Mendell, C W
  - Mendenhall, Thomas C
  - Mennie, John
  - Mennin, Peter
  - Menninger, William C
  - Menzel, Donald H
  - Merak, Kurt W (C.W.Ceram)
  - Mercer, George
  - Merdinger, C J
  - Mermin, Myer D
  - Merrill, Charles E
  - Merrill, Jacqueline
  - Messer, Thomas M
  - Messinger, Roberta
  - Metcalf, Keyes D
  - Metz, C W
  - Metzger, Samuel, III
  - Mexican Independence Anniversary Celebration
  - Mexican Minister to Peru
  - Meyer, Clara W
  - Meyer, Irving
  - Meyer, John Robert
  - Meyer, Otto
  - Micaud, Charles A F
  - Michelson, Edward J
  - Middeldorf, Ulrich
  - Middle East
  - Middlebury College
  - Mid-Hudson Legislators Announce $270,690 to 35 arts organizations
  - Midway Hospital
  - Mignoe, Francisco
  - Milbank, Dunlevy
  - Milbank Memorial Fund
  - Milford, Nancy
  - Miliet, Sergio
  - Military-Naval Club
  - Miller
  - Miller, Mrs. Audrey
  - Miller, Bernard S
  - Miller, Bess
  - Miller, C Philip
  - Miller, Carl
  - Miller, Carl B
  - Miller, Clyde R
  - Miller, D Roy
  - Miller, David C
  - Miller, Dorothy C
  - Miller, Florence
  - Miller, Francis P
  - Miller, Harry M
  - Miller, Herman, Furniture Company
  - Miller, J Roscoe
  - Miller, J W
  - Miller, James G
  - Miller, Kenneth R
  - Miller, Lewis Rex
  - Miller, Mary L
  - Miller, Merle V
  - Miller, Mildred
  - Miller, Neal E
  - Miller, Ralph R
  - Miller, Richmond P
  - Milliken, William M
  - Million, Henry A
  - Mills, Charles P., & Son
  - Mills, Fred L
  - Mills, Frederick C
  - Milne, Mrs. Katherine
  - Milton, L D
  - Mindlin, Henrique E
  - Mineka, Francis E
  - Minnesota Reunion Reception
  - Minturn, Jeannette
  - Minutes of the Policy Committee on Cultural Relations
  - Mirsky, Alfred E
  - Mirsky, Jeannette
  - Mirsky, Mrs. Reba Paeff
  - Miscellaneous notes and memoranda
  - Miscellaneous secondary material
  - Mishkin, Bernard
  - Mississippi. Tufts-Delta Health Center: A Progress Report
  - Mitchell, Harold L
  - Mitchell, Henry S
  - Mitre Hotel
  - Moe, Albert F
  - Moe, Christian Hollis
  - Moe, Mrs. Christian Hollis "Oadsie"
  - Moe, Edward C
  - Moe, Eric
  - Moe, Gordon K
  - Moe, Henry Allen
    - Acceptance of ward for distinguished service to the arts
    - Acknowledgement of Wright Brothers memorial award
    - Additional essays...
    - Address: APS and Philadelphia Museum of Art
    - Address at Pittsburgh
    - Address: Shortage of scientific Personnel
    - Address to Texas Graduate Schools
    - Address: Yale University
    - Adventure of Scholarship
    - Aspen Award convocations
    - Biographical material
    - Birthday greetings
    - Calendars
    - Career
    - Chronological file
    - Commencement address: unidentified
    - Comments on applications for fellowships
    - Communications with secretaries
    - Concerning Walker Evans, 1971
    - Condolences on death of his Mother
    - Description of Quaker Brook Farm
    - Doctor as a Citizen
    - Draft of a plan for a foundation
    - Draft of speech at a wedding dinner
    - Educated man as a citizen
    - Educational matters
    - Excerpt from last report to the John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
    - Expense accounts
    - Family
    - Family correspondence
    - Family matters
    - Family - miscellaneous
    - First meeting of the Board of Directors of the International Council at the Museum of Modern Art
    - Fortress and Greenhouse
    - Founders Day Address: Johns Hopkins Univ.
    - Freedom's Strength
    - Future speeches
    - Greetings
    - Greetings (Christmas)
    - Honoring Sarwat Okasha
    - Hospital greetings
    - Hospital Health
    - Hospital insurance
    - A Lawyer's History Lesson
    - Lecture
    - Letter in re his hospital stay
    - List of materials
    - List of speeches delivered
    - Lists
    - Mailing lists
    - Materials for a defense of Foundations
    - Memoranda for Commissioner of Internal Revenue
    - Memorial material from the Clark Foundation
    - Minutes of the Fortieth Meeting of the Educational Clinic
    - National Academy of Sciences
    - National Endowment of Humanities
    - National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities
    - Navy
    - Neither death nor taxes
    - Nomination chairman of National Endowment of the Humanities
    - Notes on H.N.'s documents
    - Notes on the Origin of Philanthropy in Christendom
    - Notes on visits to London and Portugal
    - Notes on visits to Venice and to Lafayette's home at La Grange
    - On Honors Courses
    - On the reopening of the Japanese House at the Museum of Modern Art
    - The origin of Indian corn and its relatives
    - Orthopedic problem
    - Personal correspondence - Guggenheim family
    - Personal correspondence - Restricted
    - Photographs
    - Post. From Homer to Menander (review)
    - Praise, Objection and Reproof
    - Proposal of an amendment to the Century Association
    - Press release on establishment of National Council on the Humanities
    - Profile
    - Property
    - Property at Sherman, Connecticut
    - Purchase of property in Connecticut
    - Remarks at the U.N....unveiling of mural
    - Remarks upon...receiving the Laurel Leaf Award
    - Reply to Cox Committee: Freedom's Wing.
    - Retirement
    - Retirement letters
    - Retrospect and prospect
    - Rockefeller Institute
    - Role of Museums: Smithsonian Conference on Museums and Education
    - The Second Cosmos Club Award
    - Seed Money - Guggenheim Foundation
    - Services and Honors
    - Speeches:
      - Academy of Fine Arts
      - American Association of University Women
      - and Memoranda
        - Acceptance of Laurel Leaf award
        - Association of Texas graduate schools
        - Commencement... Julliard
        - Hill School
        - I will steer my rudder true
        - MOMA, National Arts Club
        - Oneonta, New York
      - Declined
      - Diffusion of knowledge and understanding
      - The foundations and liberty
      - Honoring Captain Steichen
      - Liberating Force of Poetic Vision
      - Made
      - Memorandum to Mr. Dean Rusk
      - Money in the Public Service
      - New York State Historical Association. Annual business meeting
      - Not so much because...
      - Obligations of scholarship
      - On quality
      - Phi Beta Kappa Society
      - Power of Freedom
      - Presidential [APS] speeches
      - Proper business of colleges and foundation
      - Remarks: Museum of Modern Art. The Vision of Piers the Plowman
      - The Roger Sherman Club
      - Some clues to the open but not gullible mind
      - Southern Humanities Conference, Auburn, Ala.
      - Talk as president of the American Philosophical Society
      - Talk at the Southern Humanities Conference
      - Talk to the American Council of Learned Societies
      - Tax-exempt foundations. Answers to the questionnaire...
      - That blessed word Mesopotamia
      - To my friends at 30 Wall Street
      - To the ACLS
      - To the American Academy of Arts and Sciences
      - To the American Association for the Advancement of Science
      - To the American Council of Learned Societies
      - To the 18th annual conference of the Committee on Art Education
      - To the Walpole Society
      - Travelling Expenses
      - Tribute to Walter S. Rogers
      - U. S. Government: Reece committee
      - University of Michigan
      - Vacation
      - The vision of Piers the Plowman and the law of foundation
      - Welcome to new members (Century Association)
      - Wesleyan Commencement
      - Whyte, William H., Jr. Where the foundations fall down
  - Moe, Mrs. Henry Allen [Edith]
  - Moe, Keith
  - Moe, Ruby Sophie
  - Moe, Sherwood G
  - Moe, Thomas
  - Moe, Mrs. Thomas C
  - Mohanny, A A
  - Mohr, John Luther
  - Moll, A A
  - Mondas, Stella
  - Money-Coutts, T
  - Mongan, Agnes
  - Monge, Carlos
  - Montague, Gilbert H
  - Montero, Edwardo Bunster
  - Montgomery, Deane
  - Moog, Vianna
  - Moore, Charles A
  - Moore, Douglas
  - Moore, Mrs. Edith Simonds
  - Moore, Ethel
  - Moore, Frank C
  - Moore, Harry T
  - Moore, Henry
  - Moore, John C B
  - Moore, Merrill
  - Moore, Ruth
  - Moreno, Jenaro
  - Moreno, Samuel Ramírez
  - Morfa, R J
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company
  - Morgan, Mrs. Junius S
  - Morgan, Wesley K
  - Morison, Adele W
  - Morison, Robert S
  - Morley, Alonzo
  - Morley, Felix
  - Moross, Jerome
  - Morot-Sir, Edouard
  - Morrill Press
  - Morris, Delyte W
  - Morris, Elizabeth L
  - Morris, Max K
  - Morris, Ray
  - Morris, William
  - Morris, Willie
  - Morrison, Ann
  - Morrissey, John J
  - Morrissey, Mrs. Rosemary
  - Morshin, Fred H
  - Mort, Paul R
  - Mortensen, Carl O
  - Mortenson, Ernest R
  - Morton Arboretum
  - Morton, James
  - Moruzzi, Giuseppe
  - Mosbaugher, H G
  - Mosely, Philip E
  - Moses, Robert
  - Mott, John L
  - Mottahedeh, R Y
  - Mount Royal Hotel
  - Mounts, Charles E
  - Movado Watch Agency
  - Moyers, Bill
  - Mueller, Fred F
  - Muggah, Henry F
  - Muir, Andrew Forest
  - Mulkins, Reginald
  - Mumford, Lewis
  - Mumford, Quincy
  - Munch, Roger W
  - Munden, Ken
  - Munger, Edwin S
  - Munk, Walter H
  - Munk, Mrs. Walter H
  - Munos, Carlos
  - Munson, Mrs. John
  - Munson, Marion
  - Munson-Williams Proctor Institute
  - Murdoch, Amerco S. Albrieux
  - Murdock, George P
  - Murphy, Amos C Barstow
  - Murphy, Mrs. Grace Barstow
  - Murphy, Robert Cushman
  - Murphy, Robert D
  - Murray, Gilbert
  - Murray, Keith
  - Murray, Louis, Dance Company
  - Murrow, Edward R
  - Muse, Martha
  - Musee de Plein Air
  - Museum of the Hudson Highlands
  - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA)
    - Acquisitions lists
    - Agenda for Trustees Meeting
    - American Exhibition in Moscow
    - Annual report of the Junior Council
    - As an educational institution
    - Barr, Alfred
    - Bequest program
    - Budget
    - Building and program fund
    - Byers Committee
    - By-laws
    - Candidates for Board of Trustees
    - Certificate of incorporation of the International Council at MOMA
    - Children's Art Carnival
    - Committee on drawings and prints
    - Consultants' resumes
    - Contributors to International Symposium
    - Department of film
    - Departments and program
    - Director's report
    - Education office
    - Estimate of operating expenses for year ending 30 June 1973
    - Executive committee
    - Exhibitions
    - Facts about the Museum
    - Feasibility Survey
    - Final report to the Ford Foundation
    - Finance committee
    - Finances
    - Financial planning and control
    - Financial statement
    - Hightower, John B
    - In re meeting of Board of Trustees
    - Index to minutes: Board of Trustees
    - Institute of modern art
    - International circulating exhibitions
    - International exhibitions program
    - International council
    - International council Balance sheet
    - International council Minutes
    - International council Income and expenses
    - International council Investment committee
    - Junior council
    - Junior council Annual reports
    - Junior council Minutes
    - List of individual prospects